[Music]
hello and welcome to this tutorial
series in this series we're going to be
covering how to make a minecraft style
inventory system
in the system we're going to be able to
have a backpack chest a hot bar we're
going to pick up items from the ground
we're going to have them stack we're
going to have different max stack sizes
also going to be able to split stacks
combine stacks and drag and drop stuff
out of the inventory the way this
tutorial system is gonna work
is it split into seven parts there's
eight videos in total because i've got
like a part 5.5 which will come out
mid-week um on that week and that's a
code review so at that point in the
project i'm just going to go through all
of the code and kind of refresh
ourselves what all of the code's doing
so there's eight videos but seven parts
each video is going to come out here on
youtube weekly but the full series is
recorded and it's available over on
patreon.com so if you want early access
you can support me over on patreon and
you'll get the full series right now and
at the end of each episode i've exported
the scripts for like as they were at the
end of the episode and again if you
support over on patreon you'll get
access to the scripts as well as early
access i'll link that is in the
description below if at any point you
get kind of confused or lost you want a
bit more information leave a comment
under that video or join the discord
server which again is linked in the
description below neither me or someone
else in the community will be able to
help you hopefully solve the issue that
you're having some things that this
series isn't going to cover is just to
set expectations is there's no saving
and loading of the imagery that's almost
like a safe load system is almost its
own with this series and there are lots
of tutorials out there that would allow
you to do that but if this series is
well received and there's a lot of
support um i am thinking of doing an
expansion sort of video series to this
to show you how to make a save and load
system and save our inventories some of
the things i might do in the future with
this course is i i won't mind to do like
a shop inventory systems where you can
sell and buy items but again that's not
included in this video it's a big time
commitment to make series like this
where they're all done kind of in
advance so i didn't want to go too far
into a complex system people not like
the series so if you do and you want to
support these videos make sure you share
and like leave and comment and if
they're positively received then i will
do an expansion so save load npcs but
let's just jump into the project i'll
show you exactly what we are going to
have by the end of this course okay so
you can see that we've got our um
tomatoes here on the ground we can pick
them up and they can stack by holding
down the shift key we can split a stack
so we can take two off that stack and
halve it and see that we can now combine
stack so i can press the two and put it
on the three they become five if i split
them again so the maximum stack of these
tomatoes is five if i try and combine
the three with a three it'll fill one
stack up to its maximum and it'll leave
one stack on it on the mouse which i can
then place back down
we can also come up here and we can get
these potatoes these don't um stack at
all they've got a max stack size of one
so they just uh you know go into the
next available slot you see our hotbar
is full now if i press b and bring up
our backpack
when we start to walk over stuff now
it'll go into our backpack so i can pick
up
these other potatoes and
these are the tomatoes
so they're all soul of the tomatoes and
there's two more here so if i pick up
these
so this stack is now full and this spare
one went into our backpack
i can come over to these chests here and
open the chest and you've got our chest
panel here
this is the large chest we've also got
the small chest and this fills out
dynamically these panels don't have any
slots in them and it responds
dynamically to the inventory system that
you pass into it then of course i can
move stuff out of my backpack over into
the chest i can take out the ones from
my heart bar and place them in the chest
i can come over here and open this chest
place in some potatoes and press escape
and walk away from them go back open up
the chest and we've got our chest the
stuff that we stored in our chest here
so i can take them back out take these
potatoes out i can even split this stack
place it in here put the other part of
the stack into this chest
i can open up this chest take these back
out
and then combine them back into this
chest so with the all kind of linking
you can move stuff through dynamically
the way these work is it's not drag and
drop it's you can click once on a slot
and then it follows the mouse round and
then we can click to place it back in a
slot so this is where we're gonna be at
the end of episode seven and each uh
episode is going to cover a different
topic so parts one and two are going to
be about creating and finishing the back
end sort of code system part three we're
going to create the ui part four will be
about interacting with the ui and be
able to click on different slots part
five we're going to be splitting and
combining the stacks part 5.5 which will
come out mid-week is a code review just
to go over and make sure that we're all
on the same page with the code part six
is going to be creating the chests and
then part seven will be creating their
player backpack system so with all that
said i hope you enjoyed this series
episode one is up now on youtube as i
said the full course is already
available over on patreon and going
forward here on youtube episode two will
release in a week and then episode three
a week after that etc so make sure you
subscribe to see them as they go up and
in the meantime thanks for watching and
i'll see you in the next one bye
you